They had collected some goods for Linan Linene, who works in, who is running the Lionshield Coster full of goods and materials that they could return as a reward.
They also had Sildar Hallwinter who was very happy to see them and was willing to give them 50 gold pieces if they would just, you know, take him to town.
Right.
So Townmaster, back to Phandalin, to Phandalin.
Phandalin, okay, yes.
Sildar Hallwinter wants to go find and you also found out that Sildar Hallwinter is a member of the Lord's Alliance.
Yes, yes.
And as we discussed, the Lord's Alliance is one of the many factions in this world.
All right.
Power Protector?
The Lord's Alliance is the faction that's committed to centralized power.
To state power.
The Harpers are the ones that are committed to decentralized power.
Right?
They are aligned.
They are not aligned.
The Emerald Enclave towards the forests.
The Order of the Gauntlet.
All is good.
The Zhentarim trade is the only thing that matters.
Yes.
Right.
And as always, I have to remind you that in my campaigns, factions have factions.
Factions have factions?
Yes.
Much like in a company, not everybody is aligned.
In my campaigns, not every factions have factions.
That example was part of.
I'm sorry, I agree.
All right.
You arrive in Phandalin.
Alright, let's go to Phandalin.
Alright.
So you should be able to hear music, I hope.
If you've got the CERN skip page, you should be hearing music now.
I am on that page.
Did you hear this?
Let me click the link that you sent again.
I'll also check the volume.
Okay, can you play it now?
Also, I'll give you another, I'll just dropped another link inside here.
Maybe that link died for whatever reason.
Did you hear anything?
Yes, yes.
Alright, okay, that worked.
Alright, okay.
Can you hear now?
Yes, yes, yes.
I can hear all the birds.
Okay, cool.
Alright.
Right.
Oh, I know why I was not hearing it.
I was using a different audio setup.
Alright, okay.
Alright, so you arrived into Phandalin.
By the way, if the noise gets too loud for you, just adjust your own volume, right?
So don't.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Right, so just if you don't want to hear the music, just turn it off.
It amuses me, so I like to listen to the music.
If it bothers you, if it bothers you, feel free to turn it off.
Alright, so you're back in Phandalin.
And I'm actually, you're coming in from the north.
Let's see.
Nice party.
Alright, so you're arriving from the north.
Sildar Hallwinter, let me just make sure what Sildar Hallwinter wants to do.
I took notes.
So as you so you're arriving sort of in the late afternoon.
I mean it is a it was late evening.
The stores are mostly closed, but the Stonehill Inn is still open, so you might want to head out there to grab to grab some food and some sleep.
Alright.
Alright, hold on.
Here's Sildar Hallwinter.
Alright, so you should see a Sildar Hallwinter icon.
Yes?
Yes, yes.
Okay.
Let me make sure you can see his name.
Alright, you should be able to see his name.
Do you see his name?
Yes, I see his name.
Alright.
So you arrive.
Sildar Hallwinter is like, I'm tired.
I want to go to catch some Z's.
I don't know about the rest of you.
Shall we?
Okay, let's head it out.
What?
Well, you guys could go do something else, but I'm just saying what he wants to do is to go catch some Z's.
Yeah, okay.
So, I mean, so we'll spend some time in the Stonehill Inn tavern.
Alright.
Yep.
Okay.
Let's see what the folks have got to say.
I was expecting a hero's welcome, but no.
No hero's welcome?
Is that what you're saying?
Yeah, I was expecting maybe inside the Stonehill Inn I might.
Oh, you were expecting a hero's welcome.
Is that what I'm hearing, right?
Correct.
Is that part of the plan, or no?
You were expecting a hero's welcome, dude?
Yes, why not?
I don't know.
I kid you goblins, so.
He's like, I killed goblins, right?
Yeah.
Alright.
Maybe this is the character of Zenvon.
So Zenvon might be expecting.
Okay, so you tell that to Pip Thistlewick, right?
Like, Pip Thistlewick's like, you know, the thing about being a hero, the thing about being a hero, buddy, is that heroes.
Okay, that's a much more reasonably sized tavern.
Okay.
Even that's a little bit too big.
Yes.
Okay, there we go.
Alright.
You arrive at the tavern.
Alright, there's Tuck.
There's Elmar, who's the barkeep.
There's Freda, who's one of the locals.
There's Narth, who's another local.
Apparently, people don't have anything better to do all day.
There's Toblin.
And let's get Sildar Hallwinter.
And Sildar Hallwinter.
And let's put you.
Okay, so you should now see yourself in the inn, yes?
Which is now scaled appropriately.
Okay.
When he looks at you, Toblin says, Toblin meets you at the door.
Alright, so as you're pulling up to the inn complaining about how nobody loves you and nobody cares about you, Toblin runs out and says, Well, I'll be darned.
You brought him.
He's alive.
I didn't think anyone had.
I didn't ask anyone for the odds, but good, come in, come in, whatever you need.
It's swelling with pride.
What?
And Tuck's like, you found him!
You found him!
He didn't disappear!
And he runs up and gives you a hug.
As promised, kid.
What?
I'd promise you.
That's promised kid.
I brought him back.
Yes, and he goes, You're so good!
You're so good!
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
You're so good.
Yes.
Pip Thistlewick's like, you know, kid, it was a team sport.
I said something burning, something burning.
Are you going to like share the credit or are you going to take it all?
No, I'll, yeah, it's it's all teamwork, kid.
So everybody contributed.
Everybody contributed?
Yes.
Um.
Alright.
So he goes, so Sildar Hallwinter turns to you and says, I'd buy you a drink, but I'd suspect I'd fall asleep into it.
Tomorrow I owe you a proper conversation, a proper drink, and a proper fee.
And so he declares that he'll pay you tomorrow morning and he goes off to sleep.
What?
Okay.
So are we gonna stand here all day or are we gonna go inside and have a drink?
You go inside to have a drink, I presume, right?
Yes.
No, this is my dialogue to the Toblin.
Toblin says, ah, well, come in, come in, whatever you need.
Like, I mean, you're the heroes of the hour.
When you walk in, the locals kind of raise an eyebrow and go, well, well, well, you managed to that you managed to save some people.
The old lady, who was grouchy about the Redbrands, says, Well, it's good that you brought Sildar Hallwinter, but did you deal with the Redbrands yet?
No, not yet.
All we found was some goblins.
One of the other guys says, Well, were these goblins at all related to the Redbrands?
How do you know if goblins are related to the Redbrands?
Well, the Redbrands are a gang, and you do know that when you said I'm Glasstaff, they attacked you.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, I remember that now.
Yes, yes.
Okay, yeah, yes.
They most likely are related to the Redbrands.
Really?
Yeah.
How do you know?
We came across a bugbear.
And we managed to kill it.
Oh.
So there was a bugbear running some goblins and ambushing people along the road.
Did you hear anything else?
Anything else of any note?
So just to remind yourself, you heard about the weird goblin from Sildar Hallwinter who said the weird name.
Yeah.
There was a goblin that Sildar Hallwinter was mentioning, but I need to talk to him a little more tomorrow when he's awake.
He's pretty tired for all these things.
But yeah, so far I would say we had a pretty good run and we're the heroes.
Elmar says, well, I know when my sister comes, she's going to be an even bigger hero than you, but by golly, here's some ale for saving one of our own.
And she pours out some beer and for getting rid of those goblin bandits.
Thank you, Elmar.
Cheers.
Cheers to everyone.
Let's drink and celebrate tonight.
Then get back to the adventures tomorrow.
Alright.
Thank you for all your support and information that you guys gave.
It was helpful.
Alright.
So you guys head off to sleep.
Alright, take a long rest.
Adjust your hit points accordingly.
Points, yeah, they are 16.
Right.
You want to hit the long rest button because it resets a whole bunch of things.
Okay, yes.
Recur half head dice, record all head dice.
You know, one is the 5e rule and the other is the 5.5.
5.5, 5.5.
You said microphone is 1.
Long restaurant.
Reventability side.
So, everybody's done that?
Okay.
So,
in the morning, this is
You're like, hold on, I have a plan.
It's like people are like, this is what ruined Dungeons and Dragons.
Too much preparation.
I hope something ominous does not happen.
Right.
While you're.
So in the morning, as you're having, you come down for breakfast, right?
And in addition to, you know, and there's an there is a
NPC,
additional character.
So Sildar Hallwinter is there, and as is
background.
Sildar Hallwinter is there.
He sees you and says, Welcome, welcome, welcome.
is what happens when you have too many notes.
Come, come, come.
Let's have some breakfast.
Yes.
Let's go there.
So while you're sitting there, you also notice a guy who's like drinking beer really early in the morning.
Okay, right.
But, okay, roll an insight check or an investigation.
Did you roll?
Let me share my screen before that.
Yeah, go for it.
You see this?
Ah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay, so click OK.
Go to the features and traits part of your character sheet.
There, that's it.
So what happened?
Okay, so with the JavaScript, so this D and D Beyond D20 basically reads your local JavaScript cache.
Okay.
And so what happens is the web page only refreshes the cache when you go to the features and traits page.
Ah, I see.
Okay, okay.
So it needs you to go to the features and traits page so that the thing downloads it, so that's what it's telling you.
Just go there so it could refresh.
Okay, I went there.
I think it reflects.
Yeah, it refreshed.
That's exactly what it was doing.
All right.
Roll an investigation check.
Alright, so actually, I'm sorry, I wasn't drinking.
I got my timelines confused.
He's eating breakfast.
He's dressed like a laborer, and he's kind of like
he's got like a man like having breakfast.
Okay.
Rolling an investigation check.
Alright, what'd you roll?
It says a B.
I roll a B.
No, you couldn't have rolled the B.
You rolled the 24.
Yeah, it said B.
No, no, B.
Oh, no, B means a natural 20.
20.
Sorry.
I was pressing a 20.
Okay.
Alright.
You notice that as Toblin comes passes by, he's got a weird look on his face, as if whoever that person is is somebody dangerous.
Your instincts go that this might be somebody who works for the Redbrands.
Alright.
Okay.
So, alright.
So as you sit down, he sits down.
He goes, So, you know, I know that my poor friend, my poor friend Gundren was taken.
He's speaking to whom, Toblin, or Michael?
No, to you guys.
I'm assuming he's invited you to have breakfast with him.
So I'm assuming you're going to go sit down and have breakfast with him.
Okay.
Yeah.
I'm going to call him to our table.
Like, we are like five of us.
Why don't you come?
No, no, he had a table that had enough space for five of you.
It was almost as if he was preparing.
Like, so, sorry.
You guys arrive in the morning, right?
So let me just do this.
You arrive in the morning.
Sildar Hallwinter is already sitting there having breakfast.
The minute you walk in, he calls you to his table.
Okay, so instead of going to Sildar Hallwinter, we sit here.
Okay, yeah.
So do you want to go sit with him or not?
I want to sit with them.
Yes, we want to sit here.
Alright.
Oh, you mean Sildar Hallwinter invited to the table?
Wait, I'm confused.
Who invited us to the table?
The new guy or the.
No, Sildar Hallwinter, Sildar Hallwinter.
Okay, okay.
I'm just going to put this guy, give this guy color so that we can refer to him.
I'm going to give him the red color since you think he's a Redbrand.
Alright?
So, as you passed by this guy, you noticed him give you a weird look, and you noticed Toblin had kind of gave an even weirder look.
Alright.
So, Sildar Hallwinter says, sits down, sits down with you.
Alright, so Sildar Hallwinter says, well, as he sits down, says, this is a fine establishment with excellent food and ale.
I think you should definitely have the flapjacks.
They're pancakes.
The pancakes, right?
And so, and he goes, I have to tell, he sits down and says, well, it's a good thing, it's a good thing Gundren hired you.
And he pauses and looks at you, goes, and I have to say that I didn't really think that a rogue from the more disreputable parts of Neverwinter would be a man of his word and honor, but I guess I can always be surprised.
That actually didn't sound like a compliment.
You're quite correct.
It actually didn't sound like a compliment.
Yes.
If you're wondering what it sounded like, it did not.
He says, so, but I must tell you what I have discovered.
Gundren was taken specifically.
It was not a random robbery.
Someone told the goblins to grab Gundren and take the map.
What map?
Well, the map to the Wave Echo Cave.
What cave?
Oh, so the Wave Echo Cave is the cave.
Sorry, let me just remind you what the Wave Echo Cave is.
No, no, no.
I mean, I'm just playing along.
Oh, you're playing along.
No, I mean, he's the one who told you about the Wave Echo Cave yesterday, remember?
It's the cave that presumably is the mythical cave with lots of treasure that nobody has found and everybody thinks they're going to go find.
Right.
Here I will just so that you don't, so that you know what it is.
Let me just remind you.
Okay, so just remind you.
Right.
The three Rockseeker, brothers, Gundren, Tharden, and Nundro, recently located an entrance to the long-lost Wave Echo Cave, site of the mines of Phandelver Pact.
Alright?
And just to remind you, the Phandelver Pact
was that 500 years ago, clans of dwarves and gnomes made an agreement known as the Phandelver Pact, by which they would share a rich mine in a wondrous cavern known as the Wave Echo Cave.
Okay, so this is the first time we're hearing about the cave.
I think I told it you last time, but we can.
Here, I just put it in the story notes so you have it.
I mean, I may have for not told it to you.
I don't remember.
So this is what you are told.
Because this is the first time I'm hearing about the Phandelver Pact.
Oh, okay.
Well, then let me then hold on.
Or if this is the first time I will do it, then I hold on.
Hold on, then I will.
I will.
Okay.
Alright, so essentially, Sildar Hallwinter reads this to you.
Says this to you.
Alright, he goes.
Well, in addition to its mineral wealth, the mine contained great magical power.
Human spellcasters allied themselves with dwarves and gnomes to channel and bind the energy into a great forge called the Forge of Spells, where magic could be crafted.
Times were good, and the nearby town of Phandalin prospered as well, but disaster struck when bandits swept through the north and laid waste to all in their path.
A powerful bandit force reinforced by evil mercenary wizards attacked Wave Echo Cave to seize its riches and magic treasures.
Human wizards fought alongside their dwarf and gnome allies to defend the Forge of Spells, and the ensuing spell battle destroyed much of the cavern.
Few survived the cavens and tremors, and knowledge of the location of Wave Echo Cave was lost.
For centuries, rumors of buried riches have attracted treasure seekers and opportunists, he sneers, to the area around Phandalin, but no one has located the lost mine.
In recent years, the people resettled the area, and Phandalin is now a rough and tumble frontier town, but the Lords Alliance is going to put an end to that and bring order to this area.
And he pauses and goes, It's important to realize that Phandalin falls under the sway of his lordship Lord Neverember, and is recognized by the Lords Alliance as part of the broader area under the Lord Neverember's protection.
And any treasure that was found in the Wave Echo Cave fundamentally belongs to his lordship and the city of Neverwinter.
Interesting.
Yes, yes, yeah.
Okay, okay.
Yes.
That was a very good.
Then he goes, Recently, a trio of dwarves, the Rockseeker brothers, whom you met the oldest, discovered, claimed to have discovered the entrance to the Wave Echo Cave, and they intend to reopen the mines.
Well, unfortunately, they weren't the only ones interested in the Wave Echo Cave.
A mysterious villain who apparently controls a network of bandit gangs and goblins in the areas have followed the Rockseekers to their prize, and that is why they captured Gundren Rockseeker.
Seeker, that's how he gets his name.
Well, no, he gets his name because he was born that way.
His family, sort of an old rock seeker.
Right, right, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So, Lord, Lord Rockseeker, right?
No, Gundren Rockseeker.
No, no, no, not Gundren Rockseeker.
Like, in the fable, you mentioned Lord of the Neverwinter?
Yeah, Lord Neverember.
Neverember.
Okay, okay, okay.
Just say Lord of Neverwinter if you can't remember, or Neverember, if you can't.
Okay, okay.
Or, you know, you could say something obnoxious because you're a rogue who was a thief in his city.
Okay, yeah.
You don't have to call him.
I mean, remember, you're a rogue, and he just called you Sab just trashed you.
Right, yeah.
You don't have to call him Lord Neverember.
You can call him whatever you want, right?
Maybe not a good time to pick a fight with him, but yeah.
I'm just saying, you do not have to.
You do not have to be respectful and kind.
But there are consequences.
Alright.
So he then continues.
So you now know the story.
So he says, yes.
And it was my intention to help Sir Gundren, my dear friend, to secure the Wave Echo Cave for the benefit of the Lords Alliance and Lord Neverember and the City of Neverwinter.
Of course, Gundren would have, as a member of society, had a contract to.
What's the word I'm looking for?
To was not, he would not be left unremunerated for his discovery, but he would be seen under the overall gold goal of protecting the interests and the concerns of the Lord's Alliance.
I don't have anything to say to him.
Then he says, he goes, Now, I must say, I was not only traveling with Gundren, but I was also traveling to check on Iarno Albrek.
Yeah, I'm about to put it in there.
Right?
Okay.
A wizard and old contact who had gone to Phandalin weeks ago on Lord Alliance business and stopped sending reports.
All right.
So, is that it?
And then he goes, Can you look for Iarno?
Where was the last time you saw him?
He goes, but before any, okay, so Pip Thistlewick kind of gives you a shove.
A shove?
Yes.
But before he gives you a shove, you realize Vera, who's scribbling in her notes, says, It said Ruxithid.
And I think it said Ruxithid.
And you realize she's repeating the same name that the goblin said.
Right?
The goblin with the strange face?
Yes, yes.
All right.
She keeps saying, I think it said Ruxithid.
Now, do you look at her, ignore her?
I'm like, I'll try to whisper to her, like, what are you doing?
What are you writing?
She goes, well, I spent the entire evening rereading my notes about the elongated headed goblin by candlelight.
And then, when I wrote it down, that phrase, elongated head goblin, my blue crystal flared.
When you wrote the phrase?
Yes, yes.
Yeah, so Sister Maela goes like this, not this again.
Right?
And Pip Thistlewick kind of goes, uh-huh.
What do you do?
Is Toblin with us?
Toblin is trying to be as far away from the commoner as possible.
Okay, okay.
So, oh, that way.
Okay.
Yes.
Not towards us.
No, he's definitely trying to, like, he's even moved behind the bar and like he's trying to keep away from the commoner.
You definitely get the impression that Toblin does not want to be anywhere near that guy.
All right.
So, how do you react to Vera's Vera's comment?
Are you dismissive?
Are you interested?
Are you indifferent?
No, I'm not dismissive about it, definitely.
But
I'm going to ask to Vera, like, well, did the candle glow when the goblin said that was?
No, no, when I wrote the name down.
That's where it grew.
That was strange.
I'm telling you, there is something connected here.
And then she goes back to scribbling.
Like, after doing that, she goes back to scribbling in her notebook.
She's like, stop caring about you.
She's like, back to her notes.
Back to making circles and arrows and flipping between pages.
All right.
Then I'm going to leave her that way before I talk more.
I want to engage with Sildar.
Hold on, hold on.
But Pip, just before you engage with him, Pip goes, dude, I don't mean to be rude about this, but when somebody says, Can you go look for someone?
The first words out of your mouth should be, how much?
I mean, Pip goes, I don't, like, I'm all about doing the good deeds, but like, we also need to eat.
And he also owes us 50 gold pieces.
Plus, he turns, plus, he's a member of the Lord's Alliance.
Those guys are like swimming in cash.
We should get some money here.
Totally agree, but yeah, I need to clarify a few things before picking up anything else.
Right.
You're free to, you know, ask him for the money and volunteer to bring that guy, Iarno Albrek.
So, so he goes, so are you going to volunteer?
Are you going to ask for money?
Oh, no.
I'm telling Pip that he's free to volunteer to go bring him up.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Pip's saying you're in charge.
He's saying you've got to make sure to ask for money.
Yeah, yeah.
Don't just volunteer to do things, man.
Like, ask for money.
Okay, so yeah, I'm gonna ask Sildar, like remember, he also hasn't paid you for the 50 gold pieces he's supposed to owe you.
Just keep that in mind.
No, okay, the 15 is different from the initial 30 that I got.
Okay.
Yes.
He paid you 50 to bring you here.
Apparently, the guy is swimming in enough gold that he gave you 50 gold to do a safe walk.
Right?
And he's definitely given the impression that this is, you know, as you look at his clothes, he does not strike you as the impoverished type.
Plus, you did meet him in a fancy bar tavern in Neverwinter.
Yeah, yeah.
Fair point.
So, yeah, I'm going to ask him, like, how long do you know this guy, Iarno?
Albrek.
Yeah.
He goes, how long have I known him?
Well, quite some time.
I doubt, not on a personal level, but as a member of the Lord's Alliance, I knew him.
So he is a member of the Lord Alliance.
Yes, well, he was my agent.
I'm sorry, did I not mention that?
Yes, he was an agent of mine.
And you haven't heard from him since how long?
For years or months?
Weeks.
He was an old contact who had gone to Phandalin weeks ago on Lords of Alliance business and stopped sending reports.
Okay, I can find him for you, but I think that would be risky, and I'm, you know, putting my life at line.
So,
you know, it says, you know, he says, Iarno and I have known each other for many years.
We weren't friends.
I mean, he was a professional friend, not one that we invited to each other's families and dinners.
But, you know, I did, he says, I did recommend him for the Phandalin Constabulary Assignment.
That was as an agent of.
Do you know what a constable is?
Constable.
Yeah, yeah, the police.
Yes, I did recommend him as the for the constabulary assignment here.
We're not close friends, but you know, we are well known, and I like to think that I was a bit of a mentor for him and a friend.
On a professional level, our families didn't mix very much in society, but that's not, that wasn't to be expected.
Roll a perception, roll an insight check.
So he's not.
Are you saying that he was not important?
No, no, would you, you're a member of Neverwinter, and you know what that really means.
It means that they were different social classes.
Oh, I see.
So I'll...
No, no, you got that.
Like, I'm just saying, like, since you're from Neverwinter.
Yeah, you immediately realize, oh, shit, these guys.
In Neverwinter, there's a lot of status symbol amongst the powerful and the elites.
So he's an agent of this guy.
Okay.
Well, they're all part of the Lord's Alliance, but Sildar thinks he's better than him.
Okay, yeah.
Right.
But he's like, thinks that he's also helped Iarno, and so, and he feels responsible for Iarno in a kind of noblesse d'oblige.
Alright?
Okay, so perception.
Okay.
He then says, the other thing I want you to do, if you don't mind, find out who the Black Spider is
and find out why Gundren has gone missing.
Wow.
You gave me a bunch of tasks at the same time, and you still didn't have...
I haven't answered my question, right?
Oh, well, he goes, well, first of all, you're getting the 50 gold pieces for bringing me here safely.
So he gives you the 50 gold.
Yes, okay.
Right?
And then he says, and there will be another 200 gold pieces if you find him and bring him back safely.
Iarno, safely.
Iarno?
Okay.
And he pauses and says, and I do want to say something else.
It is the interest of the Lord's Alliance to discover who the Black Spider is, and I think that you owe a certain amount of personal loyalty to go find Gundren.
Can you elaborate a little bit on how I want to personal, you know, how am I personally loyal to Gundren?
You know, this is me talking, like, you know, trying to.
Yeah, you're basically, he goes, well, he pauses, he goes, perhaps there's no personal loyalty, but the Lord's Alliance would look very favorably on someone who brought the Black Spider to justice and rescued Gundren.
Okay.
So, with all due respect, like, this is what I think.
See, when you hired, when Gundren hired me initially, like, he did not tell me how dangerous this journey was going to be.
And I've almost put my life online, like, multiple times, like, to save you to the goblins attacker for the goods.
So, I think this is going to be more than 200.
I would be needing 500 to bring Iarno back.
Well, he goes, Iarno, he goes, that's highway robbery.
That's definitely not.
500 gold pieces is a mythical sum.
It's a mythical sum.
Like, 250, 300 gold pieces is a.
That's a lot.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
500 gold pieces is a shit ton of money.
It's kind of like, you know, 200 gold pieces is already a lot of money.
Let's settle at 300.
300, and you pay me like 150 up front right now.
Half of it up front and half after I finish the job.
He looks at you and goes, you, sir, drive a very hard bargain.
And he smiles.
50 up front, 250 when you bring, when you come, 50 up front, 150 when you bring Iarno, and 100 for Gundren.
Gundren was not part of this deal before.
So I'll take 100 up front and the 200 when I bring Iarno back.
Otherwise, you can find someone else.
Because my job ends with delivering the goods.
I also need to find who the Black Spider is and also bring Gundren back.
So there are a lot of things for me to do.
That's about prior.
Pip goes, as the man said, it's about priorities.
Pip's very pleased with you.
He's like going, he's kind of really happy.
You're standing up to this pompous bully.
Sildar sighs and hands over 100 gold.
Alright.
Yes.
So the next thing you need to go to is the Lionshield Coster to give the goods back.
I've already given in the Bath Inspiration.
Yeah, but remember you found the goods in the cave that belonged to the Lionshield Coster.
Okay.
Yes.
If you look at last week's notes, such that they are, you had returned you had found some of her missing goods among the stuff that the bandits had stolen.
Do you remember that at all?
Or did you read up on it?
No, I've been looking.
Let me just let me.
Hold on.
Hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
I know what.
Hold on.
Alright, so this was, unfortunately, I did not do recording, so I am going to...
We have to resort to the Zoom summary.
So I just updated the notes there.
Yes, okay.
This is more for you.
Alright, do you remember that now?
I'm sorry.
Yes, yes, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I recall it now, yes.
Okay.
That would be the one thing you need to do.
The other thing, there are also some other quests you can have.
The other thing is there's this guy who's looking at you, and so you can also try to decide to see if you want to follow him and see where he goes.
He's leaving the tavern now?
No, no, I'm just saying he's still in the tavern.
Like, he's slowly eating his porridge.
Like, you've never seen somebody take so long to not eat his porridge.
But yeah, I guess the goods can stay.
That's not a priority, so I'll follow him.
Well, I mean, okay, you're going to follow him?
All right.
By the way, did you order your food?
Yeah, yeah, my food just arrived.
Let me go get it.
Okay.
Alright.
So my food did arrive.
What are you doing, Andrew?
I ordered Navranta Corma and Kebab's.
Sanduri and Shi Kebab.
Oh, nice.
And from the office.
Oh, good.
Now, normally I eat a salad, but my wife's out of town and is not at home, and she only eats Indian from exactly one restaurant, which is a good restaurant, so I'm not complaining, right?
But like, it's my one day where I can eat Indian from not that place.
Well, I'm like, I like this place.
We all have our preference.
Alright.
Hold on, let me get something to drink.
Do you want to continue after we eat?
It's up to you.
Do you want to come back in 20 minutes?
Yeah, yeah, we can do that.
Alright, I will just pause.
I'll stop the recording.
I'll hang up and we'll just ping me in 20 minutes, right?
Okay.
Yeah.
Alright.
Or rather, if I get distracted, ping me in 20 minutes.
I'll ping you in 20 minutes.
Yeah, I mean, I should be back here in 20 minutes, but as I've told you before, I get distracted.
Okay.
Just like, don't, like, or call me.
Like, don't, don't worry.
I just, it's not, there's nothing going on.
It's literally, I got distracted.
Okay, yeah.
Yeah.
Okay.
Alrighty.
Let's go.
So you are still in the tavern.
So you step out the tavern.
Okay.
As you step out of the tavern.
As you step.
Okay.
So we step out of the.
I'm going to send into the change layer.
You step out of the tavern.
Where do you want to go?
To Barthen's Provisions.
Sorry, as you step out of the tavern,
the guy that you guys was following you.
Yeah, I was following him.
Yes.
You're following him, right?
Alright.
So I presume you're trying to be discreet?
Yes, I can roll the stealth.
Alright.
Roll the stilt.
Alright, roll.
Roll visual.
4 plus 7.
11.
Okay.
Alrighty.
So, as you get to a robot here, you notice.
Make sure I got this right.
Marble person.
Yeah, hold on.
You
realize that there's four guys and they're kind of holding an ambush.
You notice them.
Rather, roll your perception.
Perception,
right?
Insight investigation.
Insider investigation, sorry, insider investigation.
Oh, okay, so more perception.
Bad roll, yes.
No, don't ignore that.
Roll your investigation.
Investigations.
Ah, still bad.
No, that's 23, man.
That's very good.
Yeah, I thought it was a one.
Yeah, it was about to be a one.
One and nineteen are on opposite sides.
No.
One and twenty are on opposite sides.
Sorry.
All right.
So you see that there are four of these guys who are sort of, as you turn around the corner, you realize that there are four of them.
And the guy you were following
is kind of just standing there and looking around to see where you are.
Meanwhile, the rest of you, I presume, are sort of over here.
Okay.
The corner.
What?
Right around the corner.
Yes, right around the corner.
So I'm assuming you're right around the corner.
Alright, so Zenvon, do you want to shout and tell your friends to attack?
Do you want to go back?
Like, they're obviously out to gang up on you.
I'm gonna call my friends for help.
Do you wanna call?
Do you wanna okay?
But I need to, like, if they're not ready to engage, I'm gonna have to talk to them.
Like, who are you, guys?
Where?
Oh, that sounds like a good ambush.
Yeah, no, they clearly are looking to ambush you.
Are they not gonna engage talking with me?
Well, I mean, so it's so
you could always, like, you know, bravely and spectacularly say, Can't we just talk?
Right, yeah.
Well, okay, this is this is my response.
No, no, no, no, no, I'm just gonna say, you can do that.
He's the like this guy sort of like is waiting for to see if like the one guy who is you were who you were following is sort of waiting for you guys to to follow looks like he's looking for you guys to follow all right right and he's kind of getting disappointed
yeah okay um so when i notice the ambush uh i'm gonna ask him so looks like you were expecting me like are you not gonna introduce me to your friends oh so you that that's your routine right yeah that's that's my response yes okay roll for initiative before you do that roll an intimidation check intimidation check interesting never done this equals 19.
alrighty
let me see what happens wait is it to see that i'm intimidated or the other person is intimidated no did you intimidate him okay perfect
Alright, so you tried to intimidate him.
Yes, yes.
I got a 21.
Alright.
19.
No, I got 19 plus.
Alright, so he causes him to pause you for a second.
Oh, wait, would you try to intimidate him?
He wasn't expecting you to do that.
Uh-huh.
Right?
So he's kind of like, he's got this look where he's trying to sense your motive, see what your plans are.
So he's gonna see, wait for my plan to roll?
Yeah, he's like, yeah, you kind of like, he's not, he's paused.
He wasn't expecting you to do that.
So now he's kind of like, okay, what's your next move?
So I'll just tell him, let me bring some of my friends to introduce to you as well.
And I'm gonna call them.
Okay, so you're gonna up the intimidation level.
Up the intromination.
Yeah.
Alright, roll.
Roll the intimidation again.
Okay.
What did you get?
1 and 13.
Alright.
He goes, well, if you're going to introduce your friends, I'm going to introduce my friends.
Get him, guys!
Okay, it's going to get messy.
Fine.
It's going to get messy.
Okay.
Alright.
Initiative?
Yeah, roll for initiative.
They're a gang, right?
Yeah.
And as far as they've concerned, they were running this town, and you've shown up and are now going to tell them who they can and can't do anything to?
Oh, so these are the Redbrands.
Yeah.
You could tell they're the Redbrands because they've got red cloaks.
Oh, I'm sorry.
You didn't see them.
Sorry.
Did you not see their names now?
No, there are no names.
Okay, if I don't see names, just tell me because I didn't notice that.
Okay, so there's Redbrand Ruffian, Redbrand, Ruffian, two, three,
four.
Alright.
Yes, I see.
Yes.
Alright, so they're very impressed with your balls.
Okay.
As they should be.
Okay, now.
Gonna roll our initiative check.
Yeah, yeah, I'm gonna get a generic battle map.
914.
Yeah, I'm just gonna do something here.
So the bandits are sort of like here You're sort of over here and your guys are kind of over here Can I move these characters a little bit?
Which ones yours?
Yeah, should you should be able to so I'm thinking somewhere like this and this guy this guy was like three three squares I had three or four squares because we were talking.
Yeah, so he's right over here.
Yeah, I see one guy in corner that is fine.
And you saw all four of them, right?
Correct, yes, yes.
All three of them are in each corner, which is perfect.
Okay, cool.
Yeah, this is more like it.
Alright, cool.
Alright.
Roll for...
Why don't you roll for initiative?
I did.
I got a 14.
You got a 14?
Yes, 14.
Pip got a 20.
20 19.
Vera got a plus 2 3.
And this one.
Plus 0, 14.
You got the first emission.
So this guy here sheet.
There are only 4 in the turn order.
Just the red one.
Yeah, there's only 1 red brands.
Yeah?
Right.
Do we get an initiative turn?
So we all rolled for initiatives.
Do you see the turn order?
I see only the red brands in the turn order.
Oh, you guys, you should.
You're there, right?
No, no, that's what I'm saying.
Okay, I see what the problem is.
My bad.
Alright, I.
Yeah, no wonder you're confused.
Alright, so Zenvon had a 14, right?
I had a 14, yes.
Alright.
Sister Maela.
Pip
had a 19.
Maela Veyra had a 4.
And we'll just give her a 10.
Since I can't be bothered to.
Alright, now you should see yourselves, right?
Yes.
Alright.
Alright, good.
Alright, so everybody good now?
Yes.
Alright.
Here.
The red brand ruffians.
Right, okay.
They look like Targaryens from Game of Thrones.
What?
They look like the Targaryens from the Game of Thrones because of the blonde.
Oh, yeah, yeah, they do.
They don't they, right?
Yeah.
Alright.
So, um.
No, he wouldn't do that.
Alright, attacks Sister Maela with his short sword and does four points of damage.
Alright.
Pip.
What does Pip do?
I'm assuming he's going to
try to defend his attack.
Who do you want him to attack?
The guy that's closer to him on the right side, like on the bottom.
Alright, let me just give these guys numbers so that it's easier.
Alright,
which one?
Do you want the one that says one or two?
Two.
Alright, so Pip's going to go over here?
Yes.
Alright.
Probably a good decision.
Alright, roll.
Alright, roll to attack.
Do I roll?
Yeah, yeah, you roll, dude.
I'm like.
Over here, me.
You can either roll on.
You can either roll dice if you have dice.
If not, I will get you some dice because it always brings me joy to buy dice for players.
No, I don't have that.
Wait, wait, hold on.
I think I might have.
No, no, dude.
Or you can use the command line directly.
Yes.
I have I have this and I have this third no it's a d10 as well that's a d10 up there and yeah so just ready all right well roll roll the 20 roll to hit 18 that is a hit yes 18 is a hit all right so I'll you the way oh how much damage does he do he rolls a d8 so roll the d8 so the way you roll the d8 in you can either go into d8 these are the dice I have so I will no no but if you go like yeah so to roll it electronically you go into roll 20 yes r slash d8 yeah d8 okay slash r d8 slarry slash r d8 yes four all right so he also but uh he gets a strength bonus
no no I know what it is just hold on I have to get it I have to just
his strength bonus is plus two so he does six points of damage all right okay not bad
all right but then this other this guy here goes you arrogant you think you're you think you're so tough I'll show you what tough feels like and he attacks you with this short sword and does five points of damage
all right it's your turn I reduce my HP by five yes current max no I increase the damage to five right
you're you're yes well so it starts with your maximum and you just keep subtracting correct yeah I mean okay did you did you mark it in your character sheet yeah so there are two ways one is to increase the yeah you apply damage and the others you could do subtraction yes whatever whatever works okay yes okay five points of damage it turns out cognitively to subtraction is hard for humans all right Xenovon you're up yes now remember you've got the nick and the vex option right yes vex is like taking a big wait the damage to the next attack goes against the creature so so if you use vex your next attack can have a sneak attack bonus okay I'll do the nick the nick doesn't but you can run away without being attacked yes I'm gonna run away okay probably the right decision all right so roll an attack so you're a b20 right I'll just do this fix the task so you can crit you can click on the the
this one no wait I'm gonna use the dagger right yes so you first click on the dagger so you see where you see all the way on the left here this one yes click that do I have a disadvantage no you don't have disadvantage you only have disadvantage when you're in the dark you don't have advantage does that make sense yes okay and that is a hit for seven points of damage points yes all right okay do your second attack second attack is with the the scimitar scimitar yes
all right sister mela um shell this guy right there's one guy in the corner who has yeah he hasn't he hasn't attacked yet um sister mela looks at uh the red brand ruffian and says i'll take care of him and she attempts to attack and she misses spectacularly all right this red brand ruffian attacks thistle not thisle uh pip
pip's armor class
Armor class is uh what is armor class 16 That is a 15 that is a miss and then uh this guy
um charges straight over there.
Alright,
now it's Veyra's turn.
Alright, Vera decides that, you know what, when in doubt, cast magic missile.
Alright, she does, she kills this guy.
Oh, wow.
Well, he only had two hit points left.
Drops this guy by four and drops this guy by four.
Alrighty.
This red brand decides to attack Sister Maela again.
And he does eight points of damage.
She's hurting now.
Alright, let me just she like.
Right, okay.
So Pip, you're up.
Pip's up.
Roll for Pip's attack.
Hold on.
Before he does that, he's got a special ability.
Now, he can't use it.
Alright, go for it.
Okay, I'm gonna do another point.
Roll at D20.
Oh, you hit!
Alright, roll for damage.
D8.
Yep, D8 plus 2.
Three points of them.
Not doing very well there, Pip.
1 plus 2 is 3.
I think there's one more thing you can do.
Alright.
Zenvon, you're up.
Oh, Pip's up.
Yep.
Zenvon, you're up.
I'm up, right?
Right.
So the guy who's...
All of these guys
can be used to...
You can have sneak attack bonus.
So pick whoever you want.
Sneak attack.
That gives me remote two d6 additional points of two.
Right, so this is where if you use Vex Vex or you attack with your scimitar first.
Okay, with an advantage or just normal.
No advantage.
Which is the left one.
Okay.
And the result is.
Scimitar to hit, 19 scimitar, 4 scimitar, sneak attack, and 4.
So 8 points of damage.
Oh, hold on.
Yes.
Alright, 8.
Oh, you're a first level.
Sorry, you're not third level.
So 8 points of damage.
Well done.
Alright, now you have advantage with your second attack.
Second attack.
Okay.
So hit shift and then plus.
Oh, yeah, I got a plus now.
Okay.
Did I use a short sword?
Yes, with the...
No, with the dagger.
Dagger.
Okay.
Wait, why?
Why cannot I use the?
Oh, short swords.
Yeah, you could use the short sword.
Yeah, my bad.
You can use a short sword.
Sneak attack.
11 damage.
11 damage?
Yay.
Let me just see what this stupid meeting is.
Do we have a meeting now?
I want to see if I do.
It's 9.30 something.
I need to go to this meeting.
Okay, okay, cool.
It was good hanging out, man.
Yes, yes.
We'll catch up tomorrow.
Yes, we will.
This was a little bit of a cliffhanger.
Yeah, yeah.